scanusa.com 2007-11-20

# SCANUSA - The Secure COPS Alert Network

**Introduction**  
At SCAN USA Corporation we take privacy very seriously. Except as stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose any personally identifiable information about you without your permission. However, we may share with third parties (such as advertisers or business partners) information about you and other users of this site that has been aggregated and contains no personally identifiable information. Your continued use of this site signifies your consent to this Privacy Policy, which may be amended from time to time. If we make any material changes in this Privacy Policy, we will post an announcement on this website. 

**Information Collected**  
Although we cannot foresee all instances in which information about you may be collected through the site, currently we expect to collect information in the following circumstances:   
\-- During registration: we will collect information about you when you register to use our website;  
\-- Logging onto the site or using the desktop icon: a cookie may be stored on your computer;   
\-- Working with our technical support team: we may collect information to assist us in correcting your problem;  
\-- Entering promotions or contests that we or our partners sponsor: we may ask for information so that we can contact you should you be a winner;   
\-- Services - whether free or for a fee: when you sign up for a service from us or one of our authorized partners, we or our partners may ask you for information. If the service requires a fee, we or our partners may also need to ask you for financial information - such as a credit card number;   
\-- Optional surveys: we may ask for demographic data, or information about your use of the site.  
\-- Purchases: if you make purchases through this site, we or our business partners may ask for information necessary to complete the transaction, such as your name, address, telephone number and credit card number.

**Use of the Collected Data**  
We use the data collected about you and other users of the site on an aggregated basis to do such things as operate and enhance our offering. We also share this aggregated data with advertisers or other third parties for marketing and promotional purposes. As a general rule, we do not disclose any information that contains personally identifiable information about you to any third party without your permission. However, we may use your information to contact you directly with newsletters, notices of enhancements to the site, etc. In compliance with the CAN SPAM Act, you can elect to opt out of receiving such communications from SCAN USA. We may also share your personally identifiable information with our business partners or companies who need such information to provide a product or service requested by you. 

**Links and Co-Branded Sites**  
SCAN USA has established relationships with advertisers and reputable business partners that allow visitors to our Site to link directly to sites operated by these partners. Some of these sites may be "co-branded" with a partner logo; however, they are not operated or maintained by SCAN USA. These sites may collect personal information from you. This Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner from our partners. SCAN USA chooses its advertisers and business partners carefully. However, SCAN USA is not responsible for the content or practices of Web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our Site. These links are meant for the user's convenience only. Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval by SCAN USA of the content, policies or practices of such third party sites. We are not responsible for any information these sites may obtain and do not oversee their policies or practices in collecting personal information. Therefore, once you have left this Site via such a link, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party site. This Site may also be linked to Web sites operated by companies affiliated with SCAN USA. SCAN USA may share information collected by our affiliated companies; however, this Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we receive in this manner. Visitors to our affiliated sites should still refer to their separate privacy policies and practices when providing any personally identifiable information. 

**Special Disclosure of Information**  
We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights. We may also disclose information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our policies, or in order to protect someone who we believe may be in danger or at risk of harm.

**Some Information is Public**  
Certain areas of our site and the alert information we broadcast contain public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to publicly disclose your personal information.

**Security of Collected Information**  
We use industry standard efforts to maintain security and confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. We make reasonable business efforts to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of collected information under our control. If your account with our site is password protected, only you can access it and view the information relevant to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and any account information.

**Use of Cookies**  
Cookies are small data files stored on your computer rather than on our site. Most major websites use cookies. We may use cookies in connection with the site to help us track your use of the site. If your Internet browser allows you to refuse cookies, you may refuse to accept our site's cookies. However, doing so may prevent certain portions of the site from working properly.

**Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information from Children Under 13**   
When a visitor to our Site is under the age of 13, SCAN USA does not require the disclosure of more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary for him or her to participate in an activity as a condition of such participation. SCAN USA may use different types of personally identifiable information submitted to this Site by children under 13 in a variety of ways, which are described below. In each instance, we comply with the parental consent requirements of COPPA.

A. Use of a Child's Information by SCAN USA  
We may collect a child's email address in connection with a contest, sweepstakes or game for the sole purpose of communicating with the child on a one-time-only basis (i.e., to contact a contest winner). This information will not be used to re-contact the child, and will be deleted from our records when the contest or game is over. Parental consent is obtained before we send the winner a prize. We may collect a child's email address in order to respond more than once to a child's specific request. For example, the child may want to subscribe to an online newsletter or receive other online communications from SCAN USA. In these instances SCAN USA will also obtain a parent's email address along with the child's. Before any further contact with the child, SCAN USA will send an email to the parent (a) notifying him or her we have collected the child's email address in order to respond more than once to the child's request for a subscription, information, etc; (b) informing the parent that he or she can refuse us permission to contact the child, and how to do so; and (c) informing the parent that if he or she does not respond to the email within one (1) week, SCAN USA may use the child's information for the purpose for which it was submitted. Under no circumstances will the child be allowed to participate without giving a parent's email address. We may collect a child's personally identifiable information (including name, email address, mailing address and phone number) for such activities as chats, forums, surveys, games, bulletin boards, requests for suggestions, subscription registrations, content submissions, requests for products or services, or requests for additional information. In these instances we will initially collect only the child's name and online contact information and the email address of the child's parent. Before using this information for any purpose, we will send the parent an email that (a) informs the parent that we wish to collect and use the child's personal information and need the parent's consent to do so, and (b) provides the parent with a link to access this Privacy Policy, which describes our information collection and use policies as required by COPPA. If the proposed use of the child's personal information does not involve disclosure to a third party, then SCAN USA will ask the parent to provide consent by return email. Upon receipt of the email consent, we will send the parent a confirming email. We may collect a child's name and email address to the extent reasonably necessary to protect the security of this Site, to protect against liability or as required or permitted by law. Information collected for these reasons will not be used for any other purpose. 

B. Sharing Children's Personal Information with Third Parties  
SCAN USA may share a child's personal information with affiliated partner companies for research and marketing purposes. These companies have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of the personal information they obtain from SCAN USA. As noted above, parents must affirmatively consent to the disclosure of their child's personal information to third parties. Parents may consent to partner's collection and use of a child's personal information without consenting to the disclosure of the information to third parties.

**Contacting Us Regarding Privacy Questions**  
If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement and our practices in collecting and using information, please contact us using the following mail address or e-mail:

SCAN USA Corporation  
1127 11th Street, Suite 523  
Sacramento, CA 95814

1250 Wood Branch Park Drive, Suite 400  
Houston, TX 77079

Email us: [support@scanusa.com](mailto:support@scanusa.com)
